Angelique Evrard

VP Marketing - Founder @MarCom Institute

London W10 5SD evrard.angelique@gmail.com +44 7423 225206

Entrepreneurially-minded Franco-British senior marketer with over 15 years of experience across B2B Media and Tech companies of all sizes in the UK and internationally.

My areas of specialisation include tech events, PR, inbound, outbound, video, marketing, branding, paid, social media, digital and offline marketing, influencer, SEO/SEM, ABM and CRM. Focused on business growth using a combination of innovation, creativity and collaboration.

I have a passion for digital innovation, underpinned by traditional marketing methods. This is why I am currently studying for a certification with the Chartered Institute of Marketing (CIM).

Personal Details

Driver's License: A, Motorcycles **Eligible to work in the UK:** Yes **Highest Level of Education:** Master's

Industry: Marketing, Media & Communications

Total years of experience: 15

Work Experience

VP Marketing - Founder

MarCom Institute - Marketing and Communications Consultancy agency - London January 2022 to Present

Created my own company, freelancing for various C-level executives, helping them achieve their marketing goals, and setting their businesses up for hyper-growth and success. This venture has kept me very busy over the last 18 months. I've worked with businesses of all sizes, from start-ups to established international brands.

Past and present clients and their respective projects include: MiQ (a billion-dollar company) – leading the integration of HubSpot and Salesforce, process improvement, website revamp and marketing campaigns (Attention-based metrics), Wikimedia – creating taglines, Schbang UK – developing business strategies, UpSkill Digital – optimizing website, SEO, and SEM, Thomson Reuters (Confirmation) – oversaw social media management and email marketing, crafted unique designs using Canva, and spearheaded marketing activities utilising Salesforce, HubSpot and Marketo. In addition, I had the privilege of supporting The British Red Cross at a fundraising dinner for Ukraine.

Senior Marketing Manager and Public Relations, Global / VP Marketing

AdsWizz - Audio Advertising - London April 2021 to December 2021 As the inaugural EU Marketing hire at AdsWizz, I spearheaded global tactical Demand Generation strategies, Sales Enablement, and Sponsorship opportunity optimisation, in alignment with key KPIs.

- Crafted diverse marketing collateral that highlighted our industry-leading technologies and functionalities, adapting content to meet the needs of varied audiences: agencies, trade desks, and brands. I capitalized on my extensive network to create co-branding opportunities, thought leadership pieces, digital campaigns, and exhibition booths. This approach funnelled more leads into the Marketing pathway, a collaborative effort with our London-based PR agency.
- In collaboration with teams across Product Marketing (GTM), Engineering, Sales, Business Development, MarCom, and Executive sectors, we achieved significant, triple-figure percentage growth in the USA, EU/UK markets.

Head Marketing Communications, EMEA / VP Marketing

MediaKind (Ericsson) - TV business - London March 2020 to January 2021

At MediaKind, I championed the shift from hardware to SaaS products within the EMEA TV Media & Entertainment sector, resulting in a \$40M increase in profit. This was achieved through strategic marketing and communications initiatives, implemented in collaboration with our London-based PR and creative agencies.

- In response to the pandemic, I developed innovative pitch decks for our Spring Kind 2020 webinars, attracting over 2,600 registrants and generating substantial on-demand engagement. I also initiated the launch of our Virtual MediaKind Experience, offering an immersive virtual platform for our clients.
- Spearheaded Sports Lead Generation programs contributing to comprehensive market research, and sales support. This effort yielded our 2021 Sports D2C Forecast report, generating over 100 new sports leads. Our successful participation in the OTT Summit & SportsPro Asia 2020 led to a 300% increase in leads, securing 125+ SQLs, which resulted in 200 individual meetings.

Clients include Altice.net, Bouygues.com, Telefonica.com, Proximus.be, Libertyglobal.com, Telekom.com, TF1.fr, Sky.com, Wipro.com, Formula1.com, Veon.com, EBU.ch, NBA.com, Cloud.Google.com, AWS.com

Marketing Director, Europe / VP Marketing

TripleLift - Programmatic Native Online Advertising - London September 2017 to May 2019

As the Marketing Director of a U.S.-based programmatic native online advertising start-up, I led the growth of the Marketing Department from inception, contributing to a £15M increase in turnover in less than 1.5 years leveraging Salesforce and Looker:

- Developed and mentored a high-performing team of junior designers and freelancers, integrating global acquisitions' ad campaigns with local activations. I strengthened ties with our U.S. HQ, influencing a 15% rise in EMEA budget investment through my strategic GTM and inbound marketing initiatives.
- Helmed 20+ global events such as IAB Engage, ATS London & Paris, Cannes Lions, and more. These were monitored in Salesforce, bolstering partnerships with brands, agencies, consumers, and publishers, resulting in a 40% growth in MQLs for our Pre-Sales teams. This was achieved through the successful execution of my VSEM (Vision/Strategy/Execution and Metrics) Marketing Plan

Clients include: BBC.com, PG.co.uk, Unilever.com, IKEA.com, 20thCenturyStudios.com, EssenceMediacom.com, WavemakerGlobal.com, PublicisGroupe.com, MindshareWorld.com, Telegraph.co.uk, LeMonde.fr, TheGuardian.com, FinancialTimes.com, WashingtonPost.com, WSJ.com, Samsung.com, BMW.com, Orange.com, Philips.com

Implementation Advisor, EMEA

Khoros, previously Spredfast - Social Media Platform - London July 2016 to July 2017

Spearheaded the revitalization of over 40 SaaS social media initiatives for multicultural community engagement across Fortune 500 companies, notably accelerating a Go-to-Market project for the €64.215 billion LVMH Group. This project encompassed an integrated Earned, Owned, and Paid Social Media Strategy across Facebook, LinkedIn, Instagram, and Twitter, benefitting three LVMH Maisons - Veuve Clicquot, Moët & Chandon, and Cloudy Bay. This intensive four-month project involved collaboration with over 50 LVMH end-users and prioritized their five key European markets.

Clients include: LVMH.com, BritishAirways.com, Booking.com, MBNA.co.uk, EDF.com, PremierLeague.com, Office.co.uk, Rightmove.co.uk, Paramount.com (Viacom), NBCUniversal.com, RNLI.org, GHAdiscovery.com, Greggs.co.uk, DeBeers.co.uk, molton.brown.co.uk, TJX.com, FIVB.com, EnglandRugby.com, PublicisGroupe.com, Edelman.com, Emakina.com, AnalogFolk.com

Business Development, International Sales

Twenga - Price Comparison Website - Paris June 2015 to June 2016

Business Development, International Sales

Proxistore - Geolocalised Online Advertising - Brussels March 2014 to March 2015

Ad Operations Customer Success

Sizmek - Online Advertising - Paris June 2009 to December 2013

Various roles with Brands and Advertisers

Diageo GB - Fast Moving Consumer Goods (FMCG) - Amsterdam July 2002 to May 2009

Education

Master's degree in CIM - Marketing Leadership

Chartered Institute of Marketing - London Present

Master's Degree in International Business Management, Marketing and Communications

Université du Maine - Le Mans, FR 2002

Bachelor's Degree in International Business Management, Marketing and Communications

Université du Maine - Le Mans, FR 2001

Skills

- Marketing (10+ years)
- Social Media Marketing (10+ years)
- Google Analytics (10+ years)
- Search Engine Optimization (SEO) (10+ years)
- Customer Service (10+ years)
- Advertising (10+ years)
- Graphic Design (10+ years)
- Event Planning (10+ years)
- Public Relations (10+ years)
- Digital Marketing (10+ years)
- Salesforce (10+ years)
- HubSpot (10+ years)
- Project management (10+ years)
- B2B marketing (10+ years)
- PPC Campaign Management (10+ years)
- Microsoft Office (10+ years)
- Adobe InDesign (10+ years)
- WordPress (10+ years)
- Data analysis (10+ years)
- Customer acquisition (10+ years)
- Team management (10+ years)
- Online Marketing (10+ years)
- Email marketing (10+ years)
- Customer relationship management (10+ years)
- Marketing management (10+ years)
- Digital strategies (10+ years)
- Brand Management (10+ years)
- Integrated marketing (10+ years)
- New business development (10+ years)
- Demand generation (10+ years)
- Brand development (10+ years)
- Product development (10+ years)
- Sales management (10+ years)
- Product management (10+ years)

• Analysis skills (10+ years)

Languages

- English Fluent
- French Fluent
- Dutch Fluent
- Spanish Fluent

Links

https://marcom-institute.square.site

https://www.linkedin.com/in/angelique-evrard-marcomexpert/